<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Upasana&#39;s</title>
    <link>https://example.com/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Upasana&#39;s</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_huf4306ec19d9104fdb71fbcf65b525eb5_18040_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Upasana&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://example.com/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biochar</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/biochar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/biochar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Biochar is created through the so-called thermal breakdown of organic material at relatively low temperatures and with a constrained oxygen supply. Biochar, in a nutshell, is the carbon-rich byproduct of heating biomass, such as wood, manure, or leaves, in a closed container with little to no available air.
One of the earliest industrial technologies created by humans is the manufacturing of charcoal, which is frequently reflected in this procedure. Because there are so many different types of biomass and charring circumstances, it is considerably more challenging to define biochar from a chemical standpoint than it is from a production standpoint. The word &amp;ldquo;char&amp;rdquo; is frequently used synonymously with &amp;ldquo;charcoal,&amp;rdquo; although it is also occasionally used to describe materials that have undergone less extensive charring than charcoal.
Advantages of biochar:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biochar is a carbon-rich, stable solid that can withstand thousands of years in soil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The enormous amounts of animal dung that are produced can be disposed of using biochar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hygroscopic nature of biochar allows it to take in and retain water from its surroundings. It is therefore the perfect soil material for areas with frequent water shortages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In addition to boosting agricultural output and protecting against several foliar and soil-borne diseases, biochar increases the soil fertility of acidic soils.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potentially, fossil fuels might be replaced by the heat energy generated during the synthesis of biochar. If biochar is found to be a useful resource, it might significantly enhance air quality and help reverse the consequences of climate change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large amounts of hazardous gases are released into the environment when biomass is burned or naturally decomposed. Biochar similarly releases the same gases into the atmosphere, but the carbon content is constant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Permaculture - Remodeling agriculture system</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/permaculture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/permaculture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change&amp;rsquo;s 2019 report, a third of all greenhouse gas emissions are attributed to the world&amp;rsquo;s food production systems, which include agriculture, forestry, livestock, and other land uses. These systems produce 13% carbon dioxide, 44% methane, and 82% nitrous oxide emissions. We cannot expect agriculture to stay resilient, and as a result, the farming system urgently needs to reform. At this point, a different farming method known as &amp;ldquo;Permaculture&amp;rdquo; was developed in the 1970s by Australian biologist Bill Mollison and his student David Holmgren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of permaculture is to create long-lasting productive systems and sustainable communities that reduce the use of non-renewable energy and regulate ecological cycles. &lt;code&gt;Earth care&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;people care&lt;/code&gt;, and a &lt;code&gt;fair share&lt;/code&gt; are the three pillars of permaculture. It requires a methodical strategy based on the local environment to ensure that any systemic changes have no negative effects on the planet or its inhabitants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To adopt permaculture, we have to understand the type of the landscape, the way the water flows, the animals and trees there, and the state of the land are all made clear to us by this. It includes planning for infrastructure, a master plan, and where housing communities are located and how vegetation is grown. Methods used for this include topographical research, sound mapping, bird and tree counts, hydrological surveys, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practice of permaculture has its own special obstacles, just like any other agricultural method. Large landscapes, for example, may have different outcomes in various locations depending on how well the ecosystem is maintained there. Additionally, there is a need to motivate farmers to abandon chemical use in favor of soil conservation and restoration. Therefore, the largest issue is to comprehend and enhance the environment before deciding on food production.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydroponics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/hydroponics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/hydroponics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whenever you think of agriculture you imagine a land filled with green. Stop there! can you believe that you can grow your food in a vase that is kept near you?
Agriculture has developed so much that we can think of a world without soil. In the current situation, farmers are doing intensive agriculture and the consequence is poor soil health. Therefore, to improve the deteriorating condition of soil health we need another alternative medium for growing plants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To overcome constraints like water availability, small land holdings, disease, pest incidence, problematic soils, etc., Hydroponic techniques were innovated.
Basic Requirements of Hydroponics: Growing media, Nutrient solution, Temperature, Air, Supporting materials, Water, Mineral nutrient, and Light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hydroponic crop production has significantly increased in recent years worldwide, as it allows more efficient use of water and fertilizers, off-season production, and better control of climate and pest factors. Furthermore, hydroponic production increases crop quality and productivity, which results in higher competitiveness and economic growth.
All essential nutrients are supplied to hydroponic plants in the form of nutrient solution, which consists of fertilizer salts dissolved in water. This garden is less dirty than a normal garden because it does not require soil. As a result, there will be no thought of cleaning or killing plant insects. The main source of food for these garden plants is water and water nutrients. In such a garden, water and necessary nutrients will be provided at the root of the plant, so that the plant will survive day after day and grow quickly. Let’s take a look at some types of hydroponic gardens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Wick System&lt;/code&gt;: This type of gardening is done over a water reservoir with coconut husks or perlite (small stones). Coconut coir or perlite here draws water and supplies it to the plant roots. Reservoir water provides essential nutrients to plants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Drip System&lt;/code&gt;: This system requires only a small pump and a timer. Water flows through the drip line at the base of the plant. When the roots of the tree are dry, the timer will give the signal to run the pump. Once the pump starts running, the nutrient solution will reach the roots of the plant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Aeroponic system&lt;/code&gt;: In this case, the plant roots are dependent on air. The nutrient solution is applied to the plant&amp;rsquo;s root through continuous misting.
Nutrient Film Technique: Plants are grown in large channels where there is a regular supply of water. A timer and pump are required to keep the water flowing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ebb and flow system&lt;/code&gt;: In this method, small stones are placed in a tray, and nutrient-rich water is fed into it. Trey’s plant then gets its food from that water.
The most successful plant grown in hydroponic techniques is leafy greens, herbs, strawberries, blueberries, tomatoes, spinach, radish, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geographical Indicator</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/geographical-indication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/geographical-indication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A geographical indicator (GI) is a label placed on goods that come from a certain area and have characteristics or a reputation that are specific to that area of origin. A sign must specify that a product is from a specific location in order for it to serve as a GI. Furthermore, the origin of the product should be largely responsible for its attributes, traits, or reputation. There is an obvious connection between the product and its original site of production because the attributes are dependent on the geographic location of production. A geographical indicator right permits the owner of the right to use the indication to stop a third party from using it to market a product that doesn&amp;rsquo;t meet the relevant criteria. A protected geographical indication&amp;rsquo;s possessor is not able to stop others from producing goods using the same methods as those specified in the indication&amp;rsquo;s standards, nevertheless. Agriculture, handicrafts, food, wine &amp;amp; spirits, and industrial products are among the common categories for which geographic indications are utilised. In general, geographical indications are protected in various national and regional systems utilising a wide range of strategies, frequently combining two or more of the strategies (1. sui generis systems (i.e. special regimes of protection); 2. using collective or certification marks; and 3. methods focusing on business practices, including administrative product approval schemes). These strategies were created while taking into account various legal traditions as well as the unique historical and economic circumstances of each individual.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jute leaf - Egyptian Queen&#39;s beauty secret</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/jute_benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/jute_benefits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of Bengal&amp;rsquo;s primary crops is jute. In rural areas, jute leaf is also known as nailya leaf. But that jute leaf was mainly obtained from Tosha or Baghi jute. In addition to being low in calories, jute leaves also contain many vital vitamins and minerals, such as iron, riboflavin, folate, and vitamins A and C. It is reported that Cleopatra the Egyptian queen consumed jute leaves to maintain the health of her skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss some of the benefits of consuming jute leaf:
Cure Constipation: Jute leaves are rich in fiber. Moreover, fiber is very effective in maintaining good bowel movements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Reduce inflammation&lt;/code&gt;: Omega-3 fatty acids are found in jute leaves, which reduce inflammation. These fatty acids aid in reducing body inflammation. Additionally, the antioxidant &amp;ldquo;Lycopene&amp;rdquo; found in jute leaves aids in regenerating cells harmed by oxidation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Boost immunity&lt;/code&gt;: Vitamin C-rich jute leaves might strengthen the immune system. Additionally, vitamin C functions as a potent antioxidant that lessens the negative effects of stress, pollution, and cell oxidation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Eye and skin care&lt;/code&gt;: Vitamin A in jute leaves is good for the eyes and skin. Additionally, vitamin A is crucial for maintaining the youthfulness of the skin&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;epithelial&amp;rdquo; cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Cure for Restless Leg Syndrome&lt;/code&gt;: A person suffering from this disease keeps moving their legs constantly. One of the causes of this illness is a deficiency in iron in the body. Jute leaf consumption is frequently suggested as a natural treatment for this illness. As jute leaf is one of the rich sources of iron.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s wear Mushroom</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/mushroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/mushroom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at a biotechnology company in California, USA, discovered a ground-breaking material that will help inreducing animal cruelty. Mycelium, a component that resembles a thread, makes up a portion of the fungus&amp;rsquo;s body. According to experts, this &lt;code&gt;mycelium leather&lt;/code&gt; will be significantly more durable than regular leather. Additionally, any
shape can be selected while creating this skin, eliminating waste when using it.
Additionally, according to researchers, this leather will lessen the need for plastic and synthetic fibres in the future. As a result, the planet will be spared from the environmental damage that plastic does. Air pollution is another adverse effect of the leather business. It. Will help use to avail vegan-friendly material and reduce air pollution.
Although this invention has a lot of potential, there are some issues with it. Economically speaking, it is incredibly expensive to produce this fungus leather. As a result, only a few exclusive and pricey fashion companies can afford it. Anyways, there is currently no mass production system. Scientists are hopeful that these issues can be resolved swiftly with the help of advance scientific approach. Overall, this discovery is genuinely groundbreaking, but it won&amp;rsquo;t be clear until later how well its direct applications will work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sustainability Reporting</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/sustainability-reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/sustainability-reporting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sustainability reporting, in the business world, refers to the disclosure of non-financial performance data to external parties of the organization, whether voluntarily, upon request, or as a requirement. The capacity to reduce risk throughout an organization&amp;rsquo;s supply chain is made possible by sustainability reporting&amp;rsquo;s contribution to more effective decision-making processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benifiets of sustainability reporting are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The justification of business behaviour and the promotion of goods and services with positive social and environmental effects.Increase in corporate reputation and brand value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing a competitive edge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrating greater competitiveness by using sustainability reporting activities as a stand-in for overall performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparison and benchmarking against competitors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increasing honesty and responsibility within the organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating and sustaining staff motivation, as well as internal information and control procedures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reporting is done for a variety of purposes. First and foremost, reporting on sustainability helps make it easier to monitor progress toward predetermined goals. The implementation of the environmental strategy is then made easier as a result of the previous action. It raises awareness of general environmental challenges within the organisation. Sustainability reporting has the power to effectively communicate the corporate message both internally and internationally. Additionally, it increased overall credibility due to more transparency. It has the capability of communicating norms and efforts. It enables campaigning and operating. Finally, it provides benefits for reputation, cost savings identification, higher effectiveness, improved company development opportunities, and improved staff morale.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The cure to the deadly disease - Stroke</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/stoke/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/stoke/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The majority of population growth during the next forty years is anticipated to occur in cities, where more than half of the world&amp;rsquo;s population already resides. Most but not all studies have found that having access to green space in cities is linked to better health overall, including advantages for both physical and emotional well-being. Access to green space has been related to reduced physiological and psychological stress levels as well as cognitive repair.
Researchers found that levels of environmental pollution increase the risk of stroke. There is now a new treatment to lower the risk of stroke. People who live close to green spaces, deep forests, and other natural settings are less likely to suffer from strokes.
A Spanish research team discovered a connection between stroke propensity and a person&amp;rsquo;s proximity to a forest. According to their medical study, those who lived close to a forest were less likely to suffer a stroke. How come, though? Although it is impossible to know for sure, scientists think that being in touch with nature has numerous benefits for maintaining excellent bodily and mental health. Having plants nearby is crucial for maintaining good mental health and lowering stress. Additionally, individuals are more likely to stroll, which is good for the body, if there is a garden nearby. Furthermore, more greenery reduces pollution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where is my cup of Darjeeling tea?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/tea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The story of Darjeeling tea is unique. You won&amp;rsquo;t get its taste anywhere else. This is why Darjeeling tea is also called the &amp;lsquo;champagne of tea&amp;rsquo;. But the condition of this tea is still deteriorating. Darjeeling tea is fighting for its existence in the world market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the report, half of the tea gardens in Darjeeling are on the verge of getting sold. Due to the rising wages of labourers, falling demand for tea and prices put Darjeeling tea in trouble. Let&amp;rsquo;s find out why such a crisis has arisen in front of Darjeeling tea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, the production of Darjeeling tea has not decreased, but its buyers and value have decreased. The main reason for this is the recession. It has been observed that Europe is the main market for Darjeeling tea exports. But the situation there is getting worse. The Russia-Ukraine war has thrown European countries into disarray. Due to this, the demand for Darjeeling tea is decreasing and the tea growers are facing huge problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Labor and union protests are a common occurrence in tea gardens. It affects production as well as exports. The protests tarnished the image of Darjeeling tea gardens in the world. Some countries have reduced the demand for Darjeeling tea due to this. Among them, the most prominent name in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another well-known name in the Darjeeling tea industry is Japan. But Japan has reduced its demand. This is because of the Gorkhaland protests of 2017, which stopped tea work for about 100 days. In these difficult days, Japan shifted its focus from Darjeeling tea to Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nepal has emerged as a major tea market for many countries. Nepalese tea has already become famous both in import and export. As a result, Darjeeling tea&amp;rsquo;s production and sale suffered greatly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tea plantations here are continuously running on losses due to reduced demand for Darjeeling tea from Europe and Japan. There are reports of inferior tea being sold from Nepal and premium tea being re-exported from Darjeeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes in government regulations have also had an impact. In 2003, the government refused to give GI tags to any imported tea. In November 2021, the Tea Board issued a notification banning the distribution of second-class imported tea in the domestic market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this, the Bengal government allowed tea tourism in 15 percent of the tea plantations. Because of this, the local tea sellers are preparing to set up a resort on the tea garden land. For this, tea plantation land is being developed according to tea tourism.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://example.com/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/ik/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/ik/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The phrases &lt;code&gt;indigenous&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;traditional&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;folk knowledge&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;farmer&#39;s wisdom&lt;/code&gt;,  and/or &lt;code&gt;local knowledge&lt;/code&gt; relate to information and know-how that have been gathered through many generations and have shaped human cultures&amp;rsquo; countless interactions with their environment. Even though these names have various implications, their definitions are sufficiently consistent for us to use them interchangeably.
These knowledge systems ensure the survival of the human race by preserving the environment, guaranteeing food security, and providing early warning systems for catastrophic risk management. Indigenous knowledge is valued by the impoverished as social capital and is crucial for ensuring survival and food production. The invasion of development notions, which promise sustainable development goals or solutions, is causing the progressive extinction of local knowledge. For the native populations in the area, it is tragic that this knowledge is vanishing, and when local knowledge, skills, and teachings are lost, the repercussions can be harmful to others.
A richness of indigenous knowledge that is passed down through the generations, internalized by the communities through a process of socialization, and is a part of their way of life has been documented through anthropological investigation of numerous traditional societies in Asia and the Pacific.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
