<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Benifits | Upasana&#39;s</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/benifits/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/benifits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Benifits</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_huf4306ec19d9104fdb71fbcf65b525eb5_18040_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Benifits</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/benifits/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jute Mulching for Sustainable Agriculture</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/mulching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/mulching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While diving into the depths of jute policy for my thesis, I uncovered a gem of traditional agriculture hidden in the narratives of jute farmers from West Bengal. Their narratives did more than highlight the plant itself; they shone a light on a venerable practice—utilizing jute as a mulch, a technique that recalls a time before plastic became prevalent in farming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mulching stands as a guardian of soil health, a technique where the soil around plants is covered with a layer of material to conserve moisture, suppress weeds, and maintain soil temperature. Its role in enhancing plant growth and soil structure is unparalleled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amidst this backdrop, jute emerges as a protagonist. Biodegradable, sustainable, and enriching to the soil, jute as a mulching material is a testament to the ingenuity of traditional practices. As it decomposes, it feeds the soil, bridging the gap between past wisdom and future sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The revelation came through interviews with jute farmers for my thesis on jute policy. Their shared technique of using jute for mulching illustrated a sustainable approach deeply rooted in the fabric of their farming culture. This practice not only showcases an eco-friendly alternative to synthetic mulch but also aligns with global sustainability goals by reducing dependency on non-renewable resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we look towards a more sustainable future in agriculture, embracing jute for mulching reminds us of the value in traditional practices. It stands as a beacon for those of us seeking to blend sustainability with agricultural productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biochar</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/biochar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/biochar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Biochar is created through the so-called thermal breakdown of organic material at relatively low temperatures and with a constrained oxygen supply. Biochar, in a nutshell, is the carbon-rich byproduct of heating biomass, such as wood, manure, or leaves, in a closed container with little to no available air.
One of the earliest industrial technologies created by humans is the manufacturing of charcoal, which is frequently reflected in this procedure. Because there are so many different types of biomass and charring circumstances, it is considerably more challenging to define biochar from a chemical standpoint than it is from a production standpoint. The word &amp;ldquo;char&amp;rdquo; is frequently used synonymously with &amp;ldquo;charcoal,&amp;rdquo; although it is also occasionally used to describe materials that have undergone less extensive charring than charcoal.
Advantages of biochar:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biochar is a carbon-rich, stable solid that can withstand thousands of years in soil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The enormous amounts of animal dung that are produced can be disposed of using biochar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hygroscopic nature of biochar allows it to take in and retain water from its surroundings. It is therefore the perfect soil material for areas with frequent water shortages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In addition to boosting agricultural output and protecting against several foliar and soil-borne diseases, biochar increases the soil fertility of acidic soils.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potentially, fossil fuels might be replaced by the heat energy generated during the synthesis of biochar. If biochar is found to be a useful resource, it might significantly enhance air quality and help reverse the consequences of climate change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large amounts of hazardous gases are released into the environment when biomass is burned or naturally decomposed. Biochar similarly releases the same gases into the atmosphere, but the carbon content is constant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
