<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sustainability reporting | Upasana&#39;s</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/sustainability-reporting/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/sustainability-reporting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Sustainability reporting</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_huf4306ec19d9104fdb71fbcf65b525eb5_18040_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Sustainability reporting</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/sustainability-reporting/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>GRI</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/gri/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/gri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GRI is an independent, international organization that helps businesses and other organizations take responsibility for their impacts by providing them with a global common language to communicate those impacts through GRI standards. The GRI secretariat is headquartered in Amsterdam, the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GRI works with businesses, investors, policymakers, civil society, labor organizations, and other esports to develop the GRI standards and promote their use by organizations worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GRI standards enable any organization- large or small, private or public- to understand and report on their impact on the economy, environment, and people in a comparable and credible way, thereby increasing transparency on their contribution to sustainable development.
Now let&amp;rsquo;s understand the structure of GRI standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GRI standards are a set of multiple interlinked standards. Companies can either use the GRI standards to prepare a sustainability report following the standards, or they can use specific standards to report information to particular users or purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Universal standards
GRI 1 Requirements and principles for using the GRI standards
GRI 2 Disclosures about the reporting organization
GRI 3 Disclosures and guidance about the organization’s material topics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sector standards
GRI 11 TILL GRI 18 Provide information for organizations about their likely material topics. The organization uses sector standards that apply to its sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topic standards
GRI 201, GRI 403, GRI 305, GRI 415, GRI 303, GRI 202, GRI 304, and GRI 205 contain disclosures for the organizations to report information about its impacts concerning particular topics. The topic standards cover a wide range of issues. The organization uses the topic standards according to the list of material topics it has determined using GRI 3.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDP</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/cdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/cdp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CDP, formerly known as Carbon Disclosure Project, is a global environmental impact non-profit organization. An international non-profit organization based in the United Kingdom, Japan, India, China, Germany, and the United States of America. It has local partners across 50 countries. CDP started with the primary focus on GHG emissions and has now grown to water and forest-related issues.  It has grown to 8400 companies responding to climate change, forest, and water security questionnaires.
CDP data is extensively used by academics, businesses, Finance, and other communities in many aspects. CDP data is used to rate products and rate them. It is helpful for investors and is used to assess the carbon footprint. Also, 95% of large purchasing organizations use the data for their procurement processes. It is used to assess a company&amp;rsquo;s performance and as part of supplier evaluation and performance review.
Many groups and communities use CDP data. A 2019 survey by CDP shows that  75% of responding companies say reporting to CDP improves their reputation. The same reporting to CDP has their organization to be more competitive. CDP scoring methodology guides the companies on a journey through disclosures to awareness management and finally to leadership.  More than 200 companies have been recognized on the CDP list for climate change, forest, and water security in 2019, and “A list” is used in the STOXX low carbon Indices and the Euronext index licensed to Goldman Sachs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
