<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Upasana&#39;s</title>
    <link>https://example.com/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_huf4306ec19d9104fdb71fbcf65b525eb5_18040_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Striking a Chord for Sustainable Health - The Power of Music</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Music has long been associated with various health benefits, such as improving mental health, reducing stress and anxiety, and enhancing overall well-being. However, music can also contribute to sustainable health, promoting sustainable practices that benefit individuals and the environment. In this blog, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how music helps in sustainable health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Music and Exercise&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music has been shown to enhance physical performance and endurance, making it an excellent tool for exercise. Listening to music while exercising can help to distract from feelings of fatigue and increase motivation, making it easier to maintain a regular exercise routine. Additionally, music can help to improve the quality of exercise by increasing the level of enjoyment and reducing the perception of effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By promoting regular exercise, music can contribute to sustainable health by improving cardiovascular and respiratory function, reducing the risk of chronic disease, and enhancing overall well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Music and Mental Health&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music has a profound impact on mental health, with studies demonstrating its ability to reduce stress and anxiety, improve mood, and enhance cognitive function. Listening to calming music has been shown to decrease the levels of the stress hormone cortisol, promoting feelings of relaxation and reducing anxiety. Additionally, upbeat and energetic music can improve mood, providing an effective way to combat depression and low mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By promoting mental health, music can contribute to sustainable health by reducing the need for medical interventions, such as medication and therapy, which have significant environmental impacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Music and Community&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music has the power to bring people together, creating a sense of community and promoting social connectedness. Music events, such as concerts and festivals, provide opportunities for people to come together, share experiences, and connect with others in a meaningful way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, music can be a vehicle for social and environmental activism, raising awareness of sustainability issues and promoting positive change.
By promoting social connectedness and environmental activism, music can contribute to sustainable health by fostering a sense of community and inspiring collective action to address environmental challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, music has a significant role to play in promoting sustainable health, enhancing physical and mental well-being, promoting community, and inspiring environmental activism. As individuals, we can incorporate music into our daily lives, using it as a tool to enhance physical activity, reduce stress, and connect with others. Furthermore, we can support musicians and organizations that are committed to promoting sustainable practices, such as reducing carbon emissions and promoting social and environmental responsibility.
As a society, we can promote music education and access to music, ensuring that everyone has the opportunity to benefit from the health benefits of music. Additionally, we can support sustainable music events and organizations, promoting practices that are beneficial for both individuals and the environment. By harnessing the power of music, we can work towards a more sustainable and healthier future for all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPCC Report 2022 - A Brief</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/ipcc-2022-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/ipcc-2022-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) is a scientific body created by the United Nations to assess the risks and impacts of climate change. In August 2021, the IPCC released its Sixth Assessment Report (AR6), which is the most comprehensive and up-to-date assessment of the state of the climate, and the impacts of human activity on the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IPCC is made up of thousands of scientists and experts from around the world, who volunteer their time and expertise to conduct research and assess the latest scientific findings related to climate change. The IPCC&amp;rsquo;s reports are widely regarded as the gold standard in climate science and are used by governments, businesses, and organizations around the world to inform policy decisions and planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2022 IPCC report is a follow-up to the 2018 Special Report on Global Warming of 1.5°C, which was released ahead of the 2019 United Nations Climate Change Conference (COP25) in Madrid. The 2022 report is expected to build on the findings of the Special Report and provide updated projections and analysis of the impacts of climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2022 IPCC report is expected to cover a wide range of topics, including the latest data on global temperature trends, sea-level rise, and extreme weather events. The report will also assess the impacts of climate change on natural systems, such as oceans, ice sheets, and ecosystems, as well as on human systems, such as health, agriculture, and economies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the key areas of focus in the 2022 report will be the role of human activity in driving climate change. The report is expected to provide updated analysis on the contributions of different sectors, such as energy, transportation, and land use, to global greenhouse gas emissions. The report will also assess the potential for different scenarios, such as a rapid transition to renewable energy, to limit global warming to 1.5°C or below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2022 IPCC report is expected to provide a sobering assessment of the current state of the climate and the urgent need for action. The report is likely to highlight the significant risks and impacts of climate change, including increased heatwaves, droughts, and floods, as well as the loss of biodiversity and food insecurity. The report is also expected to stress the importance of taking immediate action to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and adapt to the impacts of climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the 2022 IPCC report is likely to be a landmark assessment of the state of the climate and the impacts of human activity on the environment. The report will provide updated analysis and projections, as well as highlighting the urgent need for action to mitigate and adapt to the impacts of climate change. The report will be an essential resource for governments, businesses, and organizations around the world as they work to tackle the climate crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ipcc.ch/report/ar6/wg2/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.ipcc.ch/report/ar6/wg2/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Fast Fashion on Environment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/fashion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/fashion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fast fashion is a term used to describe the rapid production and consumption of clothing that is designed to be trendy and disposable. The rise of fast fashion has had a significant impact on the environment, from the production of clothing to its disposal. In this blog, we will explore the impact of fast fashion on the environment and what we can do to mitigate its effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Production&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The production of fast fashion has a significant impact on the environment. The clothing industry is one of the most polluting industries in the world. The production of clothing involves the use of water, energy, and chemicals. According to the United Nations, the fashion industry is responsible for 10% of global carbon emissions, and it is the second-largest consumer of water in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The production of cotton, one of the most widely used fabrics in clothing production, requires a significant amount of water. The production of synthetic fabrics, such as polyester, also requires a significant amount of energy and the use of chemicals. The production of clothing also generates waste, with textile waste accounting for around 5% of all landfill space in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Transportation&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transportation of clothing also has an impact on the environment. The majority of clothing is produced in developing countries, such as China and Bangladesh, and then shipped to developed countries for sale. This transportation requires significant amounts of energy, contributing to greenhouse gas emissions and air pollution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Disposal&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disposal of fast fashion also has a significant impact on the environment. Clothing that is not recycled or reused is often sent to landfills, where it can take decades to decompose. The dyes and chemicals used in clothing production can leach into the soil and groundwater, polluting the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can we do to mitigate the impact of fast fashion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buy fewer clothes: One of the simplest ways to reduce the impact of fast fashion is to buy fewer clothes. Instead of buying new clothes every season, consider investing in high-quality pieces that will last for years.
Buy second-hand: Buying second-hand clothing is an excellent way to reduce the demand for new clothing. Second-hand clothing stores, online marketplaces, and clothing swaps are all great places to find gently used clothing at a fraction of the cost of new clothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose sustainable materials: Look for clothing made from sustainable materials, such as organic cotton, hemp, and recycled materials. These materials have a lower impact on the environment and are often more durable than synthetic fabrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support sustainable fashion brands: There are many sustainable fashion brands that are committed to producing clothing in an environmentally friendly way. Supporting these brands helps to reduce the demand for fast fashion and promotes sustainable practices in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, fast fashion has had a significant impact on the environment, from the production of clothing to its disposal. By buying fewer clothes, buying second-hand, choosing sustainable materials, and supporting sustainable fashion brands, we can all play a part in mitigating the impact of fast fashion on the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saltwater Power Lamp</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/saltwater-power-lamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/saltwater-power-lamp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The world is facing a significant challenge when it comes to energy. The traditional forms of energy such as fossil fuels are limited, and the need for alternative energy sources has become more critical than ever. One of the most promising alternatives is saltwater power. Saltwater power is a clean, renewable source of energy that is both abundant and accessible. One of the most exciting applications of saltwater power is in the form of a saltwater power lamp. In this blog, we will explore what a saltwater power lamp is, how it works, and its benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A saltwater power lamp is a unique lamp that uses salt water to generate electricity. The lamp works by harnessing the chemical reaction when saltwater is mixed with magnesium. When magnesium comes into contact with salt water, it creates a chemical reaction that produces electricity. This electricity is then used to power the lamp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A saltwater power lamp works through a process called electrolysis. When magnesium is placed in saltwater, it begins to corrode, and the reaction between the magnesium and the saltwater produces a flow of electrons. These electrons can be harnessed and used to power the lamp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lamp comprises two electrodes: a magnesium electrode and a copper electrode. These two electrodes are placed in the saltwater, and the reaction between the magnesium and the saltwater produces electricity. The copper electrode is connected to the lamp, and the magnesium electrode is connected to a copper wire that extends above the saltwater. The copper wire is used to switch the lamp on and off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most significant benefits of a saltwater power lamp is that it is a clean, renewable energy source. Saltwater is abundant and readily available, and the process of generating electricity from saltwater is entirely pollution-free. This makes saltwater power an environmentally friendly alternative to traditional forms of energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another benefit of a saltwater power lamp is that it is straightforward to use. The lamp does not require any batteries or an external power source. All that is needed is salt water and a magnesium electrode. The lamp can be used anywhere, making it an excellent option for camping, emergencies, or anywhere where electricity is not readily available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, a saltwater power lamp is incredibly cost-effective. The materials needed to create a saltwater power lamp are inexpensive and readily available. This makes it an affordable alternative to traditional lamps, which require expensive batteries or an external power source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, a saltwater power lamp is an innovative and exciting application of saltwater power. It is a clean, renewable source of energy that is both environmentally friendly and cost-effective. The lamp is straightforward to use and can be used anywhere, making it an excellent option for emergencies, camping, or anywhere where electricity is not readily available. The future of energy lies in alternative sources, and saltwater power is a promising and exciting option.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GRI</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/gri/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/gri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GRI is an independent, international organization that helps businesses and other organizations take responsibility for their impacts by providing them with a global common language to communicate those impacts through GRI standards. The GRI secretariat is headquartered in Amsterdam, the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GRI works with businesses, investors, policymakers, civil society, labor organizations, and other esports to develop the GRI standards and promote their use by organizations worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GRI standards enable any organization- large or small, private or public- to understand and report on their impact on the economy, environment, and people in a comparable and credible way, thereby increasing transparency on their contribution to sustainable development.
Now let&amp;rsquo;s understand the structure of GRI standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GRI standards are a set of multiple interlinked standards. Companies can either use the GRI standards to prepare a sustainability report following the standards, or they can use specific standards to report information to particular users or purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Universal standards
GRI 1 Requirements and principles for using the GRI standards
GRI 2 Disclosures about the reporting organization
GRI 3 Disclosures and guidance about the organization’s material topics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sector standards
GRI 11 TILL GRI 18 Provide information for organizations about their likely material topics. The organization uses sector standards that apply to its sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topic standards
GRI 201, GRI 403, GRI 305, GRI 415, GRI 303, GRI 202, GRI 304, and GRI 205 contain disclosures for the organizations to report information about its impacts concerning particular topics. The topic standards cover a wide range of issues. The organization uses the topic standards according to the list of material topics it has determined using GRI 3.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDP</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/cdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/cdp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CDP, formerly known as Carbon Disclosure Project, is a global environmental impact non-profit organization. An international non-profit organization based in the United Kingdom, Japan, India, China, Germany, and the United States of America. It has local partners across 50 countries. CDP started with the primary focus on GHG emissions and has now grown to water and forest-related issues.  It has grown to 8400 companies responding to climate change, forest, and water security questionnaires.
CDP data is extensively used by academics, businesses, Finance, and other communities in many aspects. CDP data is used to rate products and rate them. It is helpful for investors and is used to assess the carbon footprint. Also, 95% of large purchasing organizations use the data for their procurement processes. It is used to assess a company&amp;rsquo;s performance and as part of supplier evaluation and performance review.
Many groups and communities use CDP data. A 2019 survey by CDP shows that  75% of responding companies say reporting to CDP improves their reputation. The same reporting to CDP has their organization to be more competitive. CDP scoring methodology guides the companies on a journey through disclosures to awareness management and finally to leadership.  More than 200 companies have been recognized on the CDP list for climate change, forest, and water security in 2019, and “A list” is used in the STOXX low carbon Indices and the Euronext index licensed to Goldman Sachs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Sustainability Reporting Framework</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/international-sustainable-reporting-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/international-sustainable-reporting-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sustainability reporting is a technique for increasing transparency and responsibility in areas that regular financial reporting does not address. These include long-term perspectives and links between environmental, social, and economic challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discussion of organizational-level yearly reporting has also been expanded to include sustainability issues. In large parts of the world, publishing an annual report on financial performance is mandated by law for private and public institutions. It is given systematically and includes all pertinent financial data. To give the client of the accounts reasonable confidence regarding its completeness and correctness, and, in the public sector, to certify to the proper financial responsibility of the audited institution, a financial report or financial statement is often audited by an external auditor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though financial data may not provide a comprehensive picture of a business and the environment in which it works, corporate decision-making sometimes relies significantly on it. An organization&amp;rsquo;s success is influenced by various factors, like its ability to minimize greenhouse emissions or the effective use of its resources, in addition to its financial performance. Environmental and sustainability concerns are not simply morally troubling; they also have a growing economic relevance. Another illustration of how a company might behave is to preserve customer and staff happiness. These instances illustrate how corporate governance in the commercial sector and sound governance in the public sector are becoming increasingly important. Traditional financial reporting cannot be used to report these problems alone. Some organizations have begun to publish their performance on environmental concerns, social responsibility, or sustainable development in addition to financial issues to give a broader view of their performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the coming Blogs, I will discuss five international sustainability reporting frameworks that is CDP, GRI, SASB, IIRC, TCFD&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ecotourism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/ecotourism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/ecotourism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ecotourism is ethical travel to natural regions that preserves the environment, supports the welfare of the local community, and includes interpretation and education. Outdoor recreation, such as hiking, skiing, and camping, is a new culture nowadays. Additionally, the physical activity and health value that result from outdoor recreation can be considered important benefits of forests. Not only is there evidence that nature improves physical well-being, but it can benefit humans both psychologically and spiritually. It has been noted that many individuals consider “the forest” as a “symbolic and self-directed entity without referring to a specific place”.This emphasizes the emotional and spiritual connection humans have with forests and their importance to their well-being. Tourists visit forests for both physical and mental experiences. Therefore, it is very important to think about ecotourism and how to make it more sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ecotourism is a significant economic and educational endeavor when done properly. It has the potential to connect to a larger audience and foster conservation support while educating the general public about the value and fragility of such ecosystems. Additionally, it encourages the non-consumptive use of wilderness areas for the benefit of nearby populations that rely on these delicate environments. It entails traveling to scenic locations, which offers respite from the stressful artificial world and a momentary reprieve from the pollution of big cities. When individuals personally engage with nature, it inspires a feeling of their conservation on a personal level and fosters environmental consciousness among the tourists. It draws attention to regional and tribal traditions and fosters respect for these lesser-known cultures. Ecotourism creates jobs, offers financial help, and strengthens the local community. Ecotourism opens up a lot of chances for a developing nation in terms of environmental challenges, empowering indigenous tribes, producing jobs, and sustainable development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eco-anxiety</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/ecostress/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/ecostress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fear of ecological calamity or environmental harm is known as eco-anxiety. The environment and climate change&amp;rsquo;s present and projected future states are the basis for this fear. Instead of ignoring your emotions, try to accept them as fully valid and vital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some steps to reduce eco-anxiety:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Firstly, acknowledge your concerns about climate change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expand your knowledge related to climate crisis mitigation strategies by reading books, articles, newspapers, social media, and blogs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interact with people and share your experience with folks who understand your concerns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take action such as eating less meat, reducing water wastage, reducing food wastage, being mindful while using natural resources, and conserving energy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, creating awareness in the community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renewable Energy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/renewable-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/renewable-energy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Energy that comes from natural processes or sources that are constantly renewed is described as renewable energy. These resources are essentially limitless, even though they are only available for a short period of time each year. Sunlight, wind, geothermal energy, rain, tidal waves, etc. are a few examples. Renewable energy has long been used, for example, the sun and wind have both been used to generate heat. However, with the development of new scientific advancement, renewable energy is now defined as any natural process or source that can produce clean useable energy.A renewable energy source might be as little as a rooftop solar panel or as vast as an array of wind turbines at the seashore.The economy, ecology, national security, and human health can all benefit from renewable energy. Major oil and gas companies, private equity players, and institutional investors who prioritize renewable energy as a key component of their investment strategies are some of today ’s busy followers. These companies want to change their business models in order to benefit from the increased demand for renewables and the electrification of vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biochar</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/biochar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/biochar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Biochar is created through the so-called thermal breakdown of organic material at relatively low temperatures and with a constrained oxygen supply. Biochar, in a nutshell, is the carbon-rich byproduct of heating biomass, such as wood, manure, or leaves, in a closed container with little to no available air.
One of the earliest industrial technologies created by humans is the manufacturing of charcoal, which is frequently reflected in this procedure. Because there are so many different types of biomass and charring circumstances, it is considerably more challenging to define biochar from a chemical standpoint than it is from a production standpoint. The word &amp;ldquo;char&amp;rdquo; is frequently used synonymously with &amp;ldquo;charcoal,&amp;rdquo; although it is also occasionally used to describe materials that have undergone less extensive charring than charcoal.
Advantages of biochar:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biochar is a carbon-rich, stable solid that can withstand thousands of years in soil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The enormous amounts of animal dung that are produced can be disposed of using biochar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hygroscopic nature of biochar allows it to take in and retain water from its surroundings. It is therefore the perfect soil material for areas with frequent water shortages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In addition to boosting agricultural output and protecting against several foliar and soil-borne diseases, biochar increases the soil fertility of acidic soils.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potentially, fossil fuels might be replaced by the heat energy generated during the synthesis of biochar. If biochar is found to be a useful resource, it might significantly enhance air quality and help reverse the consequences of climate change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large amounts of hazardous gases are released into the environment when biomass is burned or naturally decomposed. Biochar similarly releases the same gases into the atmosphere, but the carbon content is constant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Permaculture - Remodeling agriculture system</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/permaculture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/permaculture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change&amp;rsquo;s 2019 report, a third of all greenhouse gas emissions are attributed to the world&amp;rsquo;s food production systems, which include agriculture, forestry, livestock, and other land uses. These systems produce 13% carbon dioxide, 44% methane, and 82% nitrous oxide emissions. We cannot expect agriculture to stay resilient, and as a result, the farming system urgently needs to reform. At this point, a different farming method known as &amp;ldquo;Permaculture&amp;rdquo; was developed in the 1970s by Australian biologist Bill Mollison and his student David Holmgren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of permaculture is to create long-lasting productive systems and sustainable communities that reduce the use of non-renewable energy and regulate ecological cycles. &lt;code&gt;Earth care&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;people care&lt;/code&gt;, and a &lt;code&gt;fair share&lt;/code&gt; are the three pillars of permaculture. It requires a methodical strategy based on the local environment to ensure that any systemic changes have no negative effects on the planet or its inhabitants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To adopt permaculture, we have to understand the type of the landscape, the way the water flows, the animals and trees there, and the state of the land are all made clear to us by this. It includes planning for infrastructure, a master plan, and where housing communities are located and how vegetation is grown. Methods used for this include topographical research, sound mapping, bird and tree counts, hydrological surveys, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practice of permaculture has its own special obstacles, just like any other agricultural method. Large landscapes, for example, may have different outcomes in various locations depending on how well the ecosystem is maintained there. Additionally, there is a need to motivate farmers to abandon chemical use in favor of soil conservation and restoration. Therefore, the largest issue is to comprehend and enhance the environment before deciding on food production.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydroponics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/hydroponics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/hydroponics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whenever you think of agriculture you imagine a land filled with green. Stop there! can you believe that you can grow your food in a vase that is kept near you?
Agriculture has developed so much that we can think of a world without soil. In the current situation, farmers are doing intensive agriculture and the consequence is poor soil health. Therefore, to improve the deteriorating condition of soil health we need another alternative medium for growing plants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To overcome constraints like water availability, small land holdings, disease, pest incidence, problematic soils, etc., Hydroponic techniques were innovated.
Basic Requirements of Hydroponics: Growing media, Nutrient solution, Temperature, Air, Supporting materials, Water, Mineral nutrient, and Light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hydroponic crop production has significantly increased in recent years worldwide, as it allows more efficient use of water and fertilizers, off-season production, and better control of climate and pest factors. Furthermore, hydroponic production increases crop quality and productivity, which results in higher competitiveness and economic growth.
All essential nutrients are supplied to hydroponic plants in the form of nutrient solution, which consists of fertilizer salts dissolved in water. This garden is less dirty than a normal garden because it does not require soil. As a result, there will be no thought of cleaning or killing plant insects. The main source of food for these garden plants is water and water nutrients. In such a garden, water and necessary nutrients will be provided at the root of the plant, so that the plant will survive day after day and grow quickly. Let’s take a look at some types of hydroponic gardens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Wick System&lt;/code&gt;: This type of gardening is done over a water reservoir with coconut husks or perlite (small stones). Coconut coir or perlite here draws water and supplies it to the plant roots. Reservoir water provides essential nutrients to plants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Drip System&lt;/code&gt;: This system requires only a small pump and a timer. Water flows through the drip line at the base of the plant. When the roots of the tree are dry, the timer will give the signal to run the pump. Once the pump starts running, the nutrient solution will reach the roots of the plant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Aeroponic system&lt;/code&gt;: In this case, the plant roots are dependent on air. The nutrient solution is applied to the plant&amp;rsquo;s root through continuous misting.
Nutrient Film Technique: Plants are grown in large channels where there is a regular supply of water. A timer and pump are required to keep the water flowing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ebb and flow system&lt;/code&gt;: In this method, small stones are placed in a tray, and nutrient-rich water is fed into it. Trey’s plant then gets its food from that water.
The most successful plant grown in hydroponic techniques is leafy greens, herbs, strawberries, blueberries, tomatoes, spinach, radish, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geographical Indicator</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/geographical-indication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/geographical-indication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A geographical indicator (GI) is a label placed on goods that come from a certain area and have characteristics or a reputation that are specific to that area of origin. A sign must specify that a product is from a specific location in order for it to serve as a GI. Furthermore, the origin of the product should be largely responsible for its attributes, traits, or reputation. There is an obvious connection between the product and its original site of production because the attributes are dependent on the geographic location of production. A geographical indicator right permits the owner of the right to use the indication to stop a third party from using it to market a product that doesn&amp;rsquo;t meet the relevant criteria. A protected geographical indication&amp;rsquo;s possessor is not able to stop others from producing goods using the same methods as those specified in the indication&amp;rsquo;s standards, nevertheless. Agriculture, handicrafts, food, wine &amp;amp; spirits, and industrial products are among the common categories for which geographic indications are utilised. In general, geographical indications are protected in various national and regional systems utilising a wide range of strategies, frequently combining two or more of the strategies (1. sui generis systems (i.e. special regimes of protection); 2. using collective or certification marks; and 3. methods focusing on business practices, including administrative product approval schemes). These strategies were created while taking into account various legal traditions as well as the unique historical and economic circumstances of each individual.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jute leaf - Egyptian Queen&#39;s beauty secret</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/jute_benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/jute_benefits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of Bengal&amp;rsquo;s primary crops is jute. In rural areas, jute leaf is also known as nailya leaf. But that jute leaf was mainly obtained from Tosha or Baghi jute. In addition to being low in calories, jute leaves also contain many vital vitamins and minerals, such as iron, riboflavin, folate, and vitamins A and C. It is reported that Cleopatra the Egyptian queen consumed jute leaves to maintain the health of her skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss some of the benefits of consuming jute leaf:
Cure Constipation: Jute leaves are rich in fiber. Moreover, fiber is very effective in maintaining good bowel movements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Reduce inflammation&lt;/code&gt;: Omega-3 fatty acids are found in jute leaves, which reduce inflammation. These fatty acids aid in reducing body inflammation. Additionally, the antioxidant &amp;ldquo;Lycopene&amp;rdquo; found in jute leaves aids in regenerating cells harmed by oxidation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Boost immunity&lt;/code&gt;: Vitamin C-rich jute leaves might strengthen the immune system. Additionally, vitamin C functions as a potent antioxidant that lessens the negative effects of stress, pollution, and cell oxidation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Eye and skin care&lt;/code&gt;: Vitamin A in jute leaves is good for the eyes and skin. Additionally, vitamin A is crucial for maintaining the youthfulness of the skin&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;epithelial&amp;rdquo; cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Cure for Restless Leg Syndrome&lt;/code&gt;: A person suffering from this disease keeps moving their legs constantly. One of the causes of this illness is a deficiency in iron in the body. Jute leaf consumption is frequently suggested as a natural treatment for this illness. As jute leaf is one of the rich sources of iron.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s wear Mushroom</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/mushroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/mushroom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at a biotechnology company in California, USA, discovered a ground-breaking material that will help inreducing animal cruelty. Mycelium, a component that resembles a thread, makes up a portion of the fungus&amp;rsquo;s body. According to experts, this &lt;code&gt;mycelium leather&lt;/code&gt; will be significantly more durable than regular leather. Additionally, any
shape can be selected while creating this skin, eliminating waste when using it.
Additionally, according to researchers, this leather will lessen the need for plastic and synthetic fibres in the future. As a result, the planet will be spared from the environmental damage that plastic does. Air pollution is another adverse effect of the leather business. It. Will help use to avail vegan-friendly material and reduce air pollution.
Although this invention has a lot of potential, there are some issues with it. Economically speaking, it is incredibly expensive to produce this fungus leather. As a result, only a few exclusive and pricey fashion companies can afford it. Anyways, there is currently no mass production system. Scientists are hopeful that these issues can be resolved swiftly with the help of advance scientific approach. Overall, this discovery is genuinely groundbreaking, but it won&amp;rsquo;t be clear until later how well its direct applications will work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sustainability Reporting</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/sustainability-reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/sustainability-reporting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sustainability reporting, in the business world, refers to the disclosure of non-financial performance data to external parties of the organization, whether voluntarily, upon request, or as a requirement. The capacity to reduce risk throughout an organization&amp;rsquo;s supply chain is made possible by sustainability reporting&amp;rsquo;s contribution to more effective decision-making processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benifiets of sustainability reporting are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The justification of business behaviour and the promotion of goods and services with positive social and environmental effects.Increase in corporate reputation and brand value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing a competitive edge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrating greater competitiveness by using sustainability reporting activities as a stand-in for overall performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparison and benchmarking against competitors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increasing honesty and responsibility within the organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating and sustaining staff motivation, as well as internal information and control procedures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reporting is done for a variety of purposes. First and foremost, reporting on sustainability helps make it easier to monitor progress toward predetermined goals. The implementation of the environmental strategy is then made easier as a result of the previous action. It raises awareness of general environmental challenges within the organisation. Sustainability reporting has the power to effectively communicate the corporate message both internally and internationally. Additionally, it increased overall credibility due to more transparency. It has the capability of communicating norms and efforts. It enables campaigning and operating. Finally, it provides benefits for reputation, cost savings identification, higher effectiveness, improved company development opportunities, and improved staff morale.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The cure to the deadly disease - Stroke</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/stoke/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/stoke/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The majority of population growth during the next forty years is anticipated to occur in cities, where more than half of the world&amp;rsquo;s population already resides. Most but not all studies have found that having access to green space in cities is linked to better health overall, including advantages for both physical and emotional well-being. Access to green space has been related to reduced physiological and psychological stress levels as well as cognitive repair.
Researchers found that levels of environmental pollution increase the risk of stroke. There is now a new treatment to lower the risk of stroke. People who live close to green spaces, deep forests, and other natural settings are less likely to suffer from strokes.
A Spanish research team discovered a connection between stroke propensity and a person&amp;rsquo;s proximity to a forest. According to their medical study, those who lived close to a forest were less likely to suffer a stroke. How come, though? Although it is impossible to know for sure, scientists think that being in touch with nature has numerous benefits for maintaining excellent bodily and mental health. Having plants nearby is crucial for maintaining good mental health and lowering stress. Additionally, individuals are more likely to stroll, which is good for the body, if there is a garden nearby. Furthermore, more greenery reduces pollution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where is my cup of Darjeeling tea?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/tea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The story of Darjeeling tea is unique. You won&amp;rsquo;t get its taste anywhere else. This is why Darjeeling tea is also called the &amp;lsquo;champagne of tea&amp;rsquo;. But the condition of this tea is still deteriorating. Darjeeling tea is fighting for its existence in the world market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the report, half of the tea gardens in Darjeeling are on the verge of getting sold. Due to the rising wages of labourers, falling demand for tea and prices put Darjeeling tea in trouble. Let&amp;rsquo;s find out why such a crisis has arisen in front of Darjeeling tea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, the production of Darjeeling tea has not decreased, but its buyers and value have decreased. The main reason for this is the recession. It has been observed that Europe is the main market for Darjeeling tea exports. But the situation there is getting worse. The Russia-Ukraine war has thrown European countries into disarray. Due to this, the demand for Darjeeling tea is decreasing and the tea growers are facing huge problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Labor and union protests are a common occurrence in tea gardens. It affects production as well as exports. The protests tarnished the image of Darjeeling tea gardens in the world. Some countries have reduced the demand for Darjeeling tea due to this. Among them, the most prominent name in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another well-known name in the Darjeeling tea industry is Japan. But Japan has reduced its demand. This is because of the Gorkhaland protests of 2017, which stopped tea work for about 100 days. In these difficult days, Japan shifted its focus from Darjeeling tea to Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nepal has emerged as a major tea market for many countries. Nepalese tea has already become famous both in import and export. As a result, Darjeeling tea&amp;rsquo;s production and sale suffered greatly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tea plantations here are continuously running on losses due to reduced demand for Darjeeling tea from Europe and Japan. There are reports of inferior tea being sold from Nepal and premium tea being re-exported from Darjeeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes in government regulations have also had an impact. In 2003, the government refused to give GI tags to any imported tea. In November 2021, the Tea Board issued a notification banning the distribution of second-class imported tea in the domestic market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this, the Bengal government allowed tea tourism in 15 percent of the tea plantations. Because of this, the local tea sellers are preparing to set up a resort on the tea garden land. For this, tea plantation land is being developed according to tea tourism.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/ik/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/ik/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The phrases &lt;code&gt;indigenous&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;traditional&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;folk knowledge&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;farmer&#39;s wisdom&lt;/code&gt;,  and/or &lt;code&gt;local knowledge&lt;/code&gt; relate to information and know-how that have been gathered through many generations and have shaped human cultures&amp;rsquo; countless interactions with their environment. Even though these names have various implications, their definitions are sufficiently consistent for us to use them interchangeably.
These knowledge systems ensure the survival of the human race by preserving the environment, guaranteeing food security, and providing early warning systems for catastrophic risk management. Indigenous knowledge is valued by the impoverished as social capital and is crucial for ensuring survival and food production. The invasion of development notions, which promise sustainable development goals or solutions, is causing the progressive extinction of local knowledge. For the native populations in the area, it is tragic that this knowledge is vanishing, and when local knowledge, skills, and teachings are lost, the repercussions can be harmful to others.
A richness of indigenous knowledge that is passed down through the generations, internalized by the communities through a process of socialization, and is a part of their way of life has been documented through anthropological investigation of numerous traditional societies in Asia and the Pacific.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
